Guide to the Robert Smythe papers, 1975-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Robert Smythe papers 1975-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Smythe, Robert.
7.9 Linear Feet Approx. 4500 Items
Natural resources consultant.
The Robert Smythe papers comprise correspondence, reports, clippings, and publications chiefly relating to Smythe's work as an officer with the North Carolina Chapter of the Sierra Club. Includes information about environmental issues in North Carolina such as air and water quality, waste management, energy conservation, and land use, as well as the Club's efforts to influence the North Carolina Legislature on environmental matters.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Robert Smythe papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1989.
Collection Overview
The Robert Smythe papers comprise correspondence, reports, clippings, and publications chiefly relating to Smythe's work as an officer with the North Carolina Chapter of the Sierra Club. Includes information about environmental issues in North Carolina such as air and water quality, waste management, energy conservation, and land use, as well as the Club's efforts to influence the North Carolina Legislature on environmental matters.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Smythe, Robert
Sierra Club. North Carolina Chapter
Environmentalists -- North Carolina -- Correspondence
Conservation of natural resources -- North Carolina
Energy conservation -- Environmental aspects
Environmental protection -- North Carolina
Environmental policy -- North Carolina
North Carolina -- Politics and government
Contents of Collection
- Robert Smythe Papers, 1975-1986, (6 boxes)
  - Horsepasture River, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Inquiries (Box 1)
  - Taskforce on waste management, 1980-1981, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Air quality, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Non-attainment (Box 1)
  - NC Energy (Box 1)
  - NC wilderness, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Alaska, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - NRCD letters (Box 1)
  - Energy (Box 2)
  - Sed. Pollution Control (Box 2)
  - Water resources (Box 2)
  - Land plan (Box 2)
  - Mining (Box 2)
  - NC Boards (Box 2)
  - Utilities companies (Box 2)
  - E. Mayo Power Plant (Box 2)
  - NC State Parks (Box 2)
  - Coastal Areas Management Act (Box 2)
  - Corrituck Banks (Box 2)
  - Corps of Engineers (Box 2)
  - Clean air and water (Box 2)
  - Letters (Box 2)
  - Sierra Club Joseph LeConte Chapter, 1979-1980, (2 notebooks) (Box 2)
  - Information, notes, 1981-1984, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Appalachia Regional Conservation Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Wilderness, 1981-1984, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - NC Legislation, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Oregon Inlet jetties, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
  - Oil refinery, Coastal Carolinas, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Coal port, Carteret County (Box 3)
  - BECO Citizens Advisory (Box 3)
  - Mosquito control, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1983, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Conservation expenses, 1983-1986, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Sierra Club National Office, 1983-1984, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Acid rain control, 1983-1986 (Box 4)
  - Bottle Bill (Box 4)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority Board, 1983-1986 (Box 4)
  - NC Energy Commission, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Radioactive waste, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Energy, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Crystalline Repository Project, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - River Protection (Box 4)
  - Detergent phosphorus ban, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Sierra Club: Mason Farm (Box 4)
  - Transportation corridor (Box 5)
  - Superfund, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
  - ARCC, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
  - NC Chapter Executive Committee, 1982-1984, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - SCCOPE, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Conservation Council of NC, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Legislative Bulletin, 1983-1984, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Oregon Inlet, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Footnotes, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - NC hazardous waste, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - NC 208 - WQMP, 1975-1979 (Box 5)
  - NC state parks, to 1980 (Box 5)
  - State parks planning, 1977-1980, (8 folders) (Box 5)
  - Alaska national interest land, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Mass transit (Box 5)
  - Crystalline rock depository (Box 6)
  - Coastal, to 1980 (Box 6)
  - Sierra membership list, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Legislation, 1979-1982, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Mining taxes NC, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Highways (Box 6)